<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lucas A. Meyer - Blog on Lucas A. Meyer - Blog</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lucas A. Meyer - Blog on Lucas A. Meyer - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Lucas A. Meyer 2016-present</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricks using Python in Azure Functions</title>
      <link>/post/installing-python-packages-in-azure-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/installing-python-packages-in-azure-functions/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about Azure Functions, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.microsoft.com/en-us/azure/azure-functions/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; is a good place to start.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Azure Functions is a serverless compute service that enables you to run code on-demand without having to explicitly provision or manage infrastructure. Use Azure Functions to run a script or piece of code in response to a variety of events. Learn how to use Azure Functions with our quickstarts, tutorials, and samples.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below I&amp;rsquo;ll describe some tricks I&amp;rsquo;ve learned to use Azure Functions with Python, which is currently (May 2018) under &amp;ldquo;experimental&amp;rdquo; support. Azure Functions, being serverless, are inexpensive but still very useful. I have used Azure Functions to create APIs for my data science projects (e.g., trigger a retraining, evaluate a submission online) and to create a Twitter Bot that posts a few random pictures every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;installing-a-more-recent-version-of-python-for-your-azure-functions&#34;&gt;Installing a more recent version of Python for your Azure Functions&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Python version in Azure Functions is pretty old. As of this writing (May 2018), it&amp;rsquo;s still on version 2.7. Let&amp;rsquo;s install version 3.5.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Open the &lt;a href=&#34;https://portal.azure.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Azure Portal&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select your function App (usually under App Services)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select &amp;ldquo;Platform Features&amp;rdquo; on top
&lt;img src=&#34;/img/python-platform.png&#34; alt=&#34;Platform Features&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select &amp;ldquo;Advanced Tools (Kudu)&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/python-kudu1.png&#34; alt=&#34;Select Kudu&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Select &amp;ldquo;CMD&amp;rdquo; on the &amp;ldquo;Debug Console&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/python-kudu.png&#34; alt=&#34;Debug Console -&amp;gt; CMD&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the fun part starts. Thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;https://ourwayoflyf.com/running-python-code-on-azure-functions-app/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Our Way of Lyf&lt;/a&gt; for providing instructions.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We first download and install Python using Nuget. To see all possible versions, please check the following website: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.siteextensions.net/profiles/steve.dower&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;https://www.siteextensions.net/profiles/steve.dower&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;nuget.exe install -Source https://www.siteextensions.net/api/v2/ -OutputDirectory D:\home\site\tools python352x64 
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For me, this step took approximately 4 minutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Successfully installed &amp;lsquo;python352x64 3.5.2.6&amp;rsquo; to D:\home\site\tools&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Executing nuget actions took 3.99 min&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;We now move Python to its proper place:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;mv /d/home/site/tools/python352x64.3.5.2.6/content/python35/* /d/home/site/tools/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From now on, whatever function we write using Python in this app will use the new version. To verify, let&amp;rsquo;s create a function using Python and check its version. Remember that in order to create Azure Functions using Python, we first have to enable &amp;ldquo;Experimental Language Support&amp;rdquo;). For this test, I&amp;rsquo;ll create a function with an HTTP trigger, which I&amp;rsquo;ll later change to a Timer trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/python-new-function.png&#34; alt=&#34;create new function&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;import os
import platform

message = &amp;quot;Using Python version {0}&amp;quot;.format(platform.python_version())
print(message)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;2018-05-30T01:34:29.954 [Info] Function started (Id=c7edfee9-b370-4dfb-bf89-2912cd09a109)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2018-05-30T01:34:35.923 [Info] Using Python version 3.5.2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2018-05-30T01:34:35.955 [Info] Function completed (Success, Id=c7edfee9-b370-4dfb-bf89-2912cd09a109, Duration=6011ms)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;installing-packages&#34;&gt;Installing packages&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have a recent version of Python, we can install whatever packages we want. For example, we can install pyodbc and python-twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;D:\home\site\tools\python.exe -m pip install pyodbc
D:\home\site\tools\python.exe -m pip install python-twitter
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With these packages installed, for example, I can connect to a SQL (or SQL Azure) database and write a Python script that tweets parts of its content.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;converting-an-http-trigger-to-a-time-trigger&#34;&gt;Converting an HTTP Trigger to a time trigger&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, Python functions don&amp;rsquo;t have a timer trigger. But that&amp;rsquo;s no big deal. Start with an HTTP trigger (see picture above), and then go to &amp;ldquo;Integrate&amp;rdquo; and delete the trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/python-delete-trigger.png&#34; alt=&#34;Delete trigger&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you delete the trigger, you&amp;rsquo;ll be able to add a new trigger, which can be a Timer trigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/python-new-trigger.png&#34; alt=&#34;Timer trigger&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can configure the trigger using the usual &lt;code&gt;cron&lt;/code&gt; syntax:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/python-timer-trigger.png&#34; alt=&#34;Configuring timer trigger&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example above, I&amp;rsquo;m triggering the function every 15 seconds. I did not change the code from before, so this will result simply in Python printing its version to the log every 15 seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/python-timer-trigger-results.png&#34; alt=&#34;Configuring timer trigger&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;a-few-ideas-on-how-to-use-this&#34;&gt;A few ideas on how to use this&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know Python and have an Azure subscription, here&amp;rsquo;s a few things that you do for free or nearly for free with this. You can:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;trigger a Python function that wakes up every day and performs some database maintentance (e.g., triggers a stored procedure that deletes old records)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;send a message in Twitter every day, for example &amp;ldquo;Since yesterday, we&amp;rsquo;ve acquired X followers&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read new data from a database, run a model that creates a forecast and save it back to the database every 2 hours&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A reflection on FY18 and FY19 plans</title>
      <link>/post/a-reflection-on-fy18-and-fy19-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-reflection-on-fy18-and-fy19-plans/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;reflecting-on-fy18-and-planning-for-fy19&#34;&gt;Reflecting on FY18 and planning for FY19&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have worked at Microsoft for long enough that it&amp;rsquo;s easier for me to make plans in tandem with the Microsoft fiscal calendar. It runs from July to June, so we&amp;rsquo;re very close to the end of FY18 and starting FY19.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fy18-recap&#34;&gt;FY18 Recap&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking back, FY18 was a year of recovery, as was FY17. We&amp;rsquo;ve had our share of health-related scares at my home, and we&amp;rsquo;re still working through some of those. However, on the positive side, it finally feels like I have some time to think (and have hope) about the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got a promotion right at the start of FY18, mostly because of my chatbot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;chatbots&#34;&gt;Chatbots&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July 2018, the very beginning of FY18, a chatbot I wrote in FY17 won the &lt;a href=&#34;http://treasurytoday.com/adamsmith/2017/winners/jc-winner-microsoft&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Adam Smith Judge&amp;rsquo;s Choice Award&lt;/a&gt;. That&amp;rsquo;s not me in the picture, by the way If I were to advertise this chatbot, I&amp;rsquo;d say its main feature is how fast it was created. It was written in about a week. Its main business feature is that it saves time by putting together information that took a few queries (and more than a few minutes) to combine. Although the chatbot could be replaced by a well-done report, it&amp;rsquo;s easier to train user to use a chatbot (the chatbot itself helps) than to use a report. This chatbot later became a platform for additional use cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This chatbot was the inspiration, and in some cases, the initial source code, for several other chatbots, including another one that won the Adam Smith award in 2018. One of the coolest features of this new chatbot is that it will ask the old chatbot when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t know the answer to a question.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;forecasting&#34;&gt;Forecasting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In another short project, I&amp;rsquo;ve created a time series forecasting platform that is used by several groups. Although it does not use super-recent time series forecasting algorithms and has quite a few restrictions on the data it can handle, it is general enough to solve a wide range of problems that we commonly face, so it was adopted by several groups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data&#34;&gt;Data&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In large companies, data can always be combined in smarter and more useful ways. In FY18 we combined such data for two large opportunities: one to help streamline sales, and another one for data mastering. Both were widely adopted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ai-school-advanced-projects&#34;&gt;AI School Advanced Projects&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In April of 2018, one of my project proposals was accepted to the AI-611 Advanced Projects course, an internal course that selects top engineers and teaches them advanced concepts in machine learning, mostly related to deep learning. The project was completed in less than two months and was recently put in production.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;conferences&#34;&gt;Conferences&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all the healthcare uncertainty, I had been out of conferences for a while. The last one I had presented was an internal conference in FY16. It&amp;rsquo;s time for a change, so I&amp;rsquo;m presenting in Baden-Baden in June 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the positive side, I&amp;rsquo;ve attended the &lt;a href=&#34;https://datascience.salon/miami11-18/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Data Science Salon&lt;/a&gt; in Miami, and it was way better than I expected it to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fy19-plans&#34;&gt;FY19 Plans&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-science-officially&#34;&gt;Data Science, officially&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For many years, I&amp;rsquo;ve been (perhaos incorrectly) proud of not being in the Data Science track at Microsoft. I was able to keep my career as &amp;ldquo;Finance&amp;rdquo;. Apparently this will change in FY19, and perhaps it&amp;rsquo;s for the better. One consequence is that I&amp;rsquo;ll be expected to publish some articles and present more in conferences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;move&#34;&gt;Move?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are advantages and disadvantages of being in a place that is a work in progress for Data Science, like Florida currently is. One of the advantages is that I can help shape how Data Science in Florida will be, and I can know many of the people in Florida that do Data Science. One disadvantage is that there&amp;rsquo;s not that many people to talk to. Florida is also very spread out, so it&amp;rsquo;s not uncommon that when something happens, it will be 90 minutes away and of uncertain quality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another disadvantage of Florida is that where we live (Broward County) doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to be an ideal place for K-12, and we are worried about the effect on the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps there&amp;rsquo;s a place with better K-12 and more Data Science in our future. Seattle would make sense, given it&amp;rsquo;s where Microsoft is, but it&amp;rsquo;s expensive enough to give us pause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;call-for-papers&#34;&gt;Call for Papers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of my likely move to a Data Science career profile, I&amp;rsquo;ll need to write papers and submit talks to conferences. Today I&amp;rsquo;ve created my &lt;a href=&#34;http://easychair.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;EasyChair&lt;/a&gt; account, but I was not fast enough to realize that most of 2018 is already gone. I&amp;rsquo;m likely going to need to create several proposals so I can have some acceptances in early 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far the ideas are:
    * The (super-cheap) Twitter Art Bot
    * Chatbots that talk to each other
    * Something about our deep learning project fro AI-611
    * Something about time-series forecasting&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;finally-a-few-challenges-for-fy19&#34;&gt;Finally, a few challenges for FY19&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Creativity is like breathing. You got to breath out, and you got to breath in. It may be time to breath out again, This coming fiscal year, I hope to have:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;24 blog posts, that is, at least two per month&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;4 presentations in local meetups&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2 external conference presentations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lenovo P51 - the Data Scientist&#39;s laptop</title>
      <link>/post/lenovo-p51-the-data-scientist-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lenovo-p51-the-data-scientist-laptop/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, as part of a computer refresh, I have moved from a Microsoft Surface Pro 3 to a Lenovo P51.
The Microsoft Surface Pro 3 was the right computer for me at the time I
got it, but as time went by my position changed substantially, and it ceased to be appropriate for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I got the Surface, the core of my work consisted in traveling, having conference calls and
light emailing and spreadsheet work. As time went by, my work went back to creating analytics,
creating presentations about analytics, and traveling. There is where the screen of the Surface
becomes a liability at 12 inches. I wanted something bigger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And boy, is the P51 bigger. It has a 15-inch screen and a power brick that alone is twice as heavy
as the Surface Pro. It&amp;rsquo;s big enough to have a keyboard that comes with a numeric keypad. Since I still
have to travel a lot, I chose the P51 over the beefier 17-inch P71. The P71 won&amp;rsquo;t even fit in my
somewhat large Osprey backpack. The P51 barely fits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to some standardization constraints, my P51 is the 1920x1080 version with touch screen. It has
32 Gb of RAM and a 500 Gb SSD. It has the i7 7820HQ running at 2.9 GHz and a Quadro M2200 GPU. If I
had the option, I&amp;rsquo;d choose the 4K screen and the Xeon processor, but I did not have that option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The battery life is surprisingly good. For the kind of things that I do in planes (writing blog posts,
editing presentations, light programming), the battery seems to last well over 8h without Wi-Fi and about 7h
with Wi-Fi. I have yet to run out of battery in a flight. I have read that the earlier version
of the P51, the P50, would trip the circuit breaker of a plane if you tried to plug it in. I have not
attempted to plug in the P51 yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The P51 is usable in the Premium Economy seats and, of course, in business and first class seats,
but I have the impression that it would not fit well in the economy class of carriers that have
a very small distance between seats (like American Airlines domestic flights), especially if the
person in front of you reclines their seat. It works well in exit seats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One gripe I had about the Surface Pro 3 was that I always had to travel with a USB hub, a mouse, and
a couple mini-DisplayPort adapters. The P51 comes with a mechanical keyboard, the beloved TrackPoint,
a good TouchPad, 4 USB ports, a Thunderbolt 3 port, an Ethernet port, an HDMI port, and, to my surprise,
a mini-DisplayPort, so I get to keep all the adapters I had for the Surface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also considered the P51-S. The slimmer version trades off some power (it goes from quad-core to
dual-core) for a thinner, lighter frame. I think the P51-S would also have been a solid choice, but I
think it would force me to do most of my work from a workstation and/or a server that I&amp;rsquo;d need to
remote into frequently, adding to the stress of versioning and synchronizing. Somewhat
counter-intuitively, I chose the heavier computer &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; I travel a lot, as it has enough power
for me to do the vast majority of my work on it and use a server or workstation just for the real
hardcore stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In summary, the Lenovo P51 is a great computer for the traveling data scientist. It&amp;rsquo;s powerful enough
to be used as your primary machine. For me, it&amp;rsquo;s near the top limit of a computer that is comfortable
to travel with, but still &lt;em&gt;within&lt;/em&gt; that limit. I got used to it in no time and completely gave up my
desktop workstation.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The three types of gifts in Buddhism</title>
      <link>/post/the-three-types-of-gifts-in-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-three-types-of-gifts-in-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From &amp;ldquo;For a future to be possible&amp;rdquo;, by Thich Nhat Hanh:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Buddhism, there are three kinds of gifts. The first is the gift of material resources. The second is to help people rely on themselves, to offer them the technology and know-how to stand on their own feet. (&amp;hellip;)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is the gift of non-fear. We are afraid of many things. We feel insecure, afraid of being alone, afraid of sickness and dying. To help people not be destroyed by their fears, we practice the third kind of gift-giving.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Irma</title>
      <link>/post/hurricane-irma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hurricane-irma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Florida has nice weather most of the time, but also has extreme weather occasionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hurricane Irma happened when I was out on a business trip, and my family was in Parkland, FL.
Forecasts went from &amp;ldquo;maybe it will hit you&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;if you stay you&amp;rsquo;ll surely die&amp;rdquo;
to &amp;ldquo;I think it&amp;rsquo;s not going to hit you anymore&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Phew, it will miss&amp;rdquo; in four days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We did a lot of preparation using conditional probabilities. In our assessment,
it would be very unlikely for the hurricane to hit both the East and West coast
simultaneously. So we decided to move the family from Parkland, FL to Tampa
(back then, the hurricane was forecasted to hit the East coast), but to book hotels
in both Pensacola (Florida panhandle) and Jacksonville, FL while we waited for new
forecasts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As days went by, the forecasts moved further and further West. On Saturday 2 AM, the
forecast was that the hurricane would hit Tampa as a Category 4, so staying there was
too risky. And then we had to decide between moving to the Florida panhandle, moving to Jacksonville
and incredibly, going back to Parkland, near Fort Lauderdale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The uncertainty seemed higher for places that were north of Tampa: it was hard to tell
whether the hurricane would turn either way in 3 days. On the other hand, the forecasts are better
in close proximity to the hurricane, and it seemed pretty certain that the hurricane would miss
the Parkland/Boca Raton area. So we made the somewhat gutsy call that my wife would come back
to Parkland with the kids.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s surely an element of luck to all of this, but the outcome was positive. We had very
minor damage in our house: a couple plants and a downspout. I think the total amount of
damage is going to be less than $100. It&amp;rsquo;s hard to be precise because there may be damage
that is hard to see, like on the roof. We did not lose power, internet or even satellite TV.
The hardest part was the stress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Monday morning the winds were back to normal. There&amp;rsquo;s still a lot of debris around the county.
I&amp;rsquo;m supposed to fly back home tomorrow, if the airport opens, and hopefully I&amp;rsquo;ll be
able to get a ride home. This was more of a suspense than a horror movie. Many people were
not as lucky as we were and we&amp;rsquo;ll now see how we can help them.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Talk</title>
      <link>/talk/example-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/talk/example-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embed your slides or video here using &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/post/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;shortcodes&lt;/a&gt;. Further details can easily be added using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deep Learning</title>
      <link>/project/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Duis posuere tellus ac convallis placerat. Proin tincidunt magna sed ex sollicitudin condimentum. Sed ac faucibus dolor, scelerisque sollicitudin nisi. Cras purus urna, suscipit quis sapien eu, pulvinar tempor diam. Quisque risus orci, mollis id ante sit amet, gravida egestas nisl. Sed ac tempus magna. Proin in dui enim. Donec condimentum, sem id dapibus fringilla, tellus enim condimentum arcu, nec volutpat est felis vel metus. Vestibulum sit amet erat at nulla eleifend gravida.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nullam vel molestie justo. Curabitur vitae efficitur leo. In hac habitasse platea dictumst. Sed pulvinar mauris dui, eget varius purus congue ac. Nulla euismod, lorem vel elementum dapibus, nunc justo porta mi, sed tempus est est vel tellus. Nam et enim eleifend, laoreet sem sit amet, elementum sem. Morbi ut leo congue, maximus velit ut, finibus arcu. In et libero cursus, rutrum risus non, molestie leo. Nullam congue quam et volutpat malesuada. Sed risus tortor, pulvinar et dictum nec, sodales non mi. Phasellus lacinia commodo laoreet. Nam mollis, erat in feugiat consectetur, purus eros egestas tellus, in auctor urna odio at nibh. Mauris imperdiet nisi ac magna convallis, at rhoncus ligula cursus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cras aliquam rhoncus ipsum, in hendrerit nunc mattis vitae. Duis vitae efficitur metus, ac tempus leo. Cras nec fringilla lacus. Quisque sit amet risus at ipsum pharetra commodo. Sed aliquam mauris at consequat eleifend. Praesent porta, augue sed viverra bibendum, neque ante euismod ante, in vehicula justo lorem ac eros. Suspendisse augue libero, venenatis eget tincidunt ut, malesuada at lorem. Donec vitae bibendum arcu. Aenean maximus nulla non pretium iaculis. Quisque imperdiet, nulla in pulvinar aliquet, velit quam ultrices quam, sit amet fringilla leo sem vel nunc. Mauris in lacinia lacus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a tincidunt lacus. Curabitur at urna sagittis, dictum ante sit amet, euismod magna. Sed rutrum massa id tortor commodo, vitae elementum turpis tempus. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit. Aenean purus turpis, venenatis a ullamcorper nec, tincidunt et massa. Integer posuere quam rutrum arcu vehicula imperdiet. Mauris ullamcorper quam vitae purus congue, quis euismod magna eleifend. Vestibulum semper vel augue eget tincidunt. Fusce eget justo sodales, dapibus odio eu, ultrices lorem. Duis condimentum lorem id eros commodo, in facilisis mauris scelerisque. Morbi sed auctor leo. Nullam volutpat a lacus quis pharetra. Nulla congue rutrum magna a ornare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aliquam in turpis accumsan, malesuada nibh ut, hendrerit justo. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Quisque sed erat nec justo posuere suscipit. Donec ut efficitur arcu, in malesuada neque. Nunc dignissim nisl massa, id vulputate nunc pretium nec. Quisque eget urna in risus suscipit ultricies. Pellentesque odio odio, tincidunt in eleifend sed, posuere a diam. Nam gravida nisl convallis semper elementum. Morbi vitae felis faucibus, vulputate orci placerat, aliquet nisi. Aliquam erat volutpat. Maecenas sagittis pulvinar purus, sed porta quam laoreet at.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>External Project</title>
      <link>/project/example-external-project/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/example-external-project/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My complicated relationship with the second amendment</title>
      <link>/post/my-complicated-relationship-with-the-second-amendment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-complicated-relationship-with-the-second-amendment/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m writing this on 2018-02-26, after thinking a lot about guns after the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stoneman_Douglas_High_School_shooting&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Parkland School Shooting&lt;/a&gt;,
but I&amp;rsquo;m burying this article in the past because there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of passion around this topic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I live in Parkland, FL, and I have three kids. When the Parkland School Shooting happened, my kids were in elementary school, and out of danger. Many of our friends and
their kids were not so lucky as we were. I used to take for granted that my kids would come back from school every day, unharmed. Now I don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also a registered Republican, but I&amp;rsquo;m not a conservative by any means. My ideas align strongly with the Libertarian movement. Many libertarian ideas align with
the Republican party, but not all: for example, libertarians abhor the swelling of the military and police that happens during Republican terms.
On the other hands, libertarians are fierce defenders of individual rights, including the right to bear arms.
Although I lean strong libertarian, I don&amp;rsquo;t like guns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This does not mean that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have a gun or that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t shoot someone that was a threat to my life or the life of a family member.
If the best option was using lethal force, I&amp;rsquo;m fairly sure I would use it. I just wouldn&amp;rsquo;t like it.
On the other hand, I think society would be much simpler if guns were rare and less lethal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I don&amp;rsquo;t like guns, as long as the Second Amendment is in the Constitution, I will support it. I would also support repealing it. A representative
that has a platform of repealing the Second Amendment has my attention and likely my vote. A representative that wants to &lt;em&gt;limit&lt;/em&gt; the Second Amendment, on the other hand,
doesn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is probably hard to understand. People are usually &amp;ldquo;pro-gun&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;anti-gun&amp;rdquo;, and that&amp;rsquo;s it. Anything that scores points for your team is good. But
the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.billofrightsinstitute.org/founding-documents/bill-of-rights/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Bill of Rights&lt;/a&gt; are not just for one team. They are the rules of the game.
I don&amp;rsquo;t like restricting the Second Amendment in a similar way that I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t like having some type of penalty being called only against my team. Heck,
even if it was the other team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rights should be extremely hard to restrict. I think we lost that battle with the Fourth Amendment. Instead of going through the painful motions of
repealing a right, reaction to some event erodes the right little by little, until the right is a shell of what it was. Although I don&amp;rsquo;t like guns
and shouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind that erosion happening with the Second Amendment, I do. Because I care about our rights. I don&amp;rsquo;t think we would have such a great
country without the rights we do, and I also don&amp;rsquo;t think the country can continue to be great if rights can easily be restricted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may think &amp;ldquo;but high-powered weapons are &lt;em&gt;evil&lt;/em&gt;&amp;rdquo;, and it may feel like that to many, including me. But if you start transferring that logic to
other rights, then it may not make as much sense. The government may get the power to ban high-powered weapons. It may get the power to ban high-powered
speech. It may get the power to ban jury trials on &amp;ldquo;high-powered crimes&amp;rdquo;. The poor Fourth Amendment is
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.duicentral.com/dui/the-dui-exception/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;full of holes&lt;/a&gt; already.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This may sound like a &amp;lsquo;slippery slope&amp;rsquo; argument. It&amp;rsquo;s not. I&amp;rsquo;m not arguing that &lt;em&gt;because&lt;/em&gt; we restrict one right we may get better at restrict others. I&amp;rsquo;m arguing that
the bar to restrict any right should be ludicrously high, even if I don&amp;rsquo;t like them. And it has not been consistently high.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/marcorubio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Marco Rubio&lt;/a&gt;, the future former Florida Senator, bless his heart, posted
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nytimes.com/2015/10/04/opinion/sunday/nicholas-kristof-a-new-way-to-tackle-gun-deaths.html?smprod=nytcore-ipad&amp;amp;smid=nytcore-ipad-share&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;
from the New York Times on Twitter. The article is full of good ideas, but idiotic: comparing driving with the Second Amendment is disingenuous.
The Second Amendment is a right, driving isn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am for repealing the Second Amendment, but not restricting it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Person Re-Identification System For Mobile Devices</title>
      <link>/publication/person-re-identification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/person-re-identification/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile visual clothing search</title>
      <link>/publication/clothing-search/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/publication/clothing-search/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;More detail can easily be written here using &lt;em&gt;Markdown&lt;/em&gt; and $\rm \LaTeX$ math code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
