<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Lucas A. Meyer - Blog</title>
    <link>/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Lucas A. Meyer - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Lucas A. Meyer 2016-present</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Centralized vs. Distributed Data Science Teams</title>
      <link>/post/centralized-vs-distributed-data-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/centralized-vs-distributed-data-teams/</guid>
      <description>In a recent DataFramed podcast, Hugo Bowne-Anderson and Jonathan Nolis discuss whether data scientist teams should be centralized or distributed. I have my own opinions about that question.
Should data science teams be centralized or distributed? I was happy to find that Jonathan Nolis has the same opinion as I do: that a data science team works best when distributed into client areas. In addition, we agree that if you distribute your data science team among several different client areas, you have to find a way of keeping the data scientists feeling as if they&amp;rsquo;re part of a cohesive group.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frankfurt - Spring 2018</title>
      <link>/post/frankfurt-spring-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/frankfurt-spring-2018/</guid>
      <description>I gave two short talks for the 10th Arvato Financial Services Telekommunikationsforum in Baden-Baden. The way ticket prices worked out, it was US$ 1000 cheaper to return on Sunday than it was to return on Saturday, so I was able to spend a full day in Frankfurt.
I hope to come back.
A great base for European adventures One of the things I liked the most about Frankfurt was how integrated the transportation system was.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tricks using Python in Azure Functions</title>
      <link>/post/installing-python-packages-in-azure-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/installing-python-packages-in-azure-functions/</guid>
      <description>If you don&amp;rsquo;t know anything about Azure Functions, this is a good place to start.
 Azure Functions is a serverless compute service that enables you to run code on-demand without having to explicitly provision or manage infrastructure. Use Azure Functions to run a script or piece of code in response to a variety of events. Learn how to use Azure Functions with our quickstarts, tutorials, and samples.
 Here are some tricks to use Azure Functions with Python, which is currently (May 2018) under &amp;ldquo;experimental&amp;rdquo; support.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A reflection on FY18 and FY19 plans</title>
      <link>/post/a-reflection-on-fy18-and-fy19-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/a-reflection-on-fy18-and-fy19-plans/</guid>
      <description>Reflecting on FY18 and planning for FY19 I have worked at Microsoft for long enough that it&amp;rsquo;s easier for me to make plans in tandem with the Microsoft fiscal calendar. It runs from July to June, so we&amp;rsquo;re very close to the end of FY18 and starting FY19.
FY18 Recap Looking back, FY18 was a year of recovery, as was FY17. We&amp;rsquo;ve had our share of health-related scares at my home, and we&amp;rsquo;re still working through some of those.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lenovo P51 - the Data Scientist&#39;s laptop</title>
      <link>/post/lenovo-p51-the-data-scientist-laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/lenovo-p51-the-data-scientist-laptop/</guid>
      <description>Recently, as part of a computer refresh, I have moved from a Microsoft Surface Pro 3 to a Lenovo P51. The Microsoft Surface Pro 3 was the right computer for me at the time I got it, but as time went by my position changed substantially, and it ceased to be appropriate for me.
When I got the Surface, the core of my work consisted in traveling, having conference calls and light emailing and spreadsheet work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The three types of gifts in Buddhism</title>
      <link>/post/the-three-types-of-gifts-in-buddhism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-three-types-of-gifts-in-buddhism/</guid>
      <description>From &amp;ldquo;For a future to be possible&amp;rdquo;, by Thich Nhat Hanh:
 In Buddhism, there are three kinds of gifts. The first is the gift of material resources. The second is to help people rely on themselves, to offer them the technology and know-how to stand on their own feet. (&amp;hellip;)
The third is the gift of non-fear. We are afraid of many things. We feel insecure, afraid of being alone, afraid of sickness and dying.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hurricane Irma</title>
      <link>/post/hurricane-irma/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hurricane-irma/</guid>
      <description>Florida has nice weather most of the time, but also has extreme weather occasionally.
Hurricane Irma happened when I was out on a business trip, and my family was in Parkland, FL. Forecasts went from &amp;ldquo;maybe it will hit you&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;if you stay you&amp;rsquo;ll surely die&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;I think it&amp;rsquo;s not going to hit you anymore&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;Phew, it will miss&amp;rdquo; in four days.
We did a lot of preparation using conditional probabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My complicated relationship with the second amendment</title>
      <link>/post/my-complicated-relationship-with-the-second-amendment/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/my-complicated-relationship-with-the-second-amendment/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m writing this on 2018-02-26, after thinking a lot about guns after the Parkland School Shooting, but I&amp;rsquo;m burying this article in the past because there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of passion around this topic.
 I live in Parkland, FL, and I have three kids. When the Parkland School Shooting happened, my kids were in elementary school, and out of danger. Many of our friends and their kids were not so lucky as we were.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>